Anika Tahsin Chowdhury Simi

<u>anikachy4@gmail.com</u> | <u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/anikatahsinchowdhury-software-engineer/</u> | Dublin, Ireland(Eligible to work full-time(Stamp 1G)) | +353 89 4324861

SUMMARY

I have developed a deep understanding of Algorithms and Data Structures and have received recognition for my performance in several national Programming Contests. Throughout my professional career, I have gained experience in iOS development, making contributions to Samsung's iOS applications like Samsung Galaxy Wearable, Samsung Galaxy-Buds, and SmartThings. My enthusiasm lies in adopting new technologies and creating creative solutions for challenging issues.

TECHNOLOGIES AND LANGUAGES

- **Programming Languages:** C/C++, Swift, Familiar with JavaScript, HTML, CSS(Working knowledge).
- Technology: iOS Application Development, Xcode, Git, Agile Scrum.
- Additional skills: Problem Solving, Algorithms and Data Structures.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant(Part-time)

University College Dublin

Aug 2023 — Dec 2023

- Conducted thorough research, gathered data, and performed detailed analysis to uncover patterns and insights, maintaining data accuracy and reliability.
- Investigated, compiled, and examined data to detect trends and insights, ensuring the precision and dependability of the data.
- Design and developed website of HOLOS-IE using internal tools and technologies of UCD

Software Engineer

Samsung R&D Institute Bangladesh

Apr 2019 — Aug 2022

- Contributed to the development and improvement of the Samsung SmartThings Scan Nearby feature, resulting in increased user satisfaction and onboarding efficiency.
- Developed Backend Driven UI with RESTful API integration and implemented new features of UI Screens for the Samsung Galaxy Wearable, which includes the ability to connect to mobile devices and facilitate data backup and restoration using Samsung Account.
- Developed new-feature of Samsung Galaxy Buds, such as Equalizer
- Adhered to Test-Driven Development practices to increase code stablity and making less bug .
- Improved and fixed bugs in the SmartThings Help Card, enhancing the user experience.
- Successfully applied refactoring techniques to significantly reduce the Cyclomatic and Cognitive Complexity of the SmartThings codebase by 85%, resulting in improved code quality and maintainability.
- Demonstrated strong independent problem-solving skills by developing UI and Utility modules and writing Unit tests for the Samsung Galaxy Wearable and SmartThings projects.

PROJECTS

- <u>iBooks</u>: iBooks is Developed using Swift in Xcode. The app is a Backend-Driven UI implementation, used mock-server to fetch book list and details, with handling exception occurences.
- <u>Todo-list</u>: Designed and developed an web Application Todo list using React JS.It allows user to create and modify their day to day task.

EDUCATION

Leading University, Sylhet, Bangladesh

Oct 2016 — Mar 2019

Bachelor of Science - Computer Science and Engineering

Sylhet International University

Apr 2014 — Oct 2016

Bachelor of Science - Computer Science and Engineering

AWARDS

328th place at Google Code Jam to I/O for Women, Google

Aug 2018

10th Place at DIU National Girls Programming Contest, Daffodil International University

Aug 2017

9th - NSU IUGPC 2018, North South University

Apr 2018

23rd LU National ICT Fest Programming Contest, Leading University

Dec 2018